In 1942 everyone loved a soldier
Yanks is a romance, drama, war film directed by John Schlesinger.
During WWII, the United States set up army bases in
Great Britain as part of the war effort.
Against their proper sensibilities, many of the Brits don't much like the brash Yanks,
especially when it comes to the G.I.s making advances on the lonely British girls.
One relationship that develops is between married John, an Army Captain, and
the aristocratic Helen, whose naval husband is away at war.
Helen loves her husband, but Helen and John are looking for
some comfort during the difficult times.
Matt Dyson, played by Richard Gere.
Jean Moreton, played by Lisa Eichhorn.
Helen, played by Vanessa Redgrave.
John, played by William Devane.
Danny Ruffelo, played by Chick Vennera.
Mollie, played by Wendy Morgan.
Yanks is a 1979 drama film directed by John Schlesinger, and produced by Joseph Janni
and Lester Persky, and is written by Colin Welland and Walter Bernstein.
It stars Richard Gere, Lisa Eichhorn, Vanessa Redgrave, William Devane,
Chick Vennera, Wendy Morgan, Rachel Roberts and Tony Melody.
The film is set during the Second World War in Northern
England and features no combat scenes.
The film depicts the relationships between American soldiers stationed in semi-rural England
and the local population during the build-up to Operation Overlord in 1944.
In particular, three romances between US service personnel and local women are shown, in order to explore the effects
of the cultural differences between the brash GIs or "Yanks" and the more reserved British population.
The world premiere was held on 1 June 1979 at a cinema in Bournemouth, England.
Lisa Eichhorn was present at the premiere, which had invited returning D-Day veterans
from many American divisions - most notably the American 29th Division.
Leader of the returning 29ers was Sgt Curtis C.
Williams who was 19 on D-Day.
The film explores themes of new year's eve, northern
england, england, world war ii, prejudice.
The tone is emotional.